Hey! Quit slackin' off!
Эй, не бездельничать!
Hey, cabin boys! After sweeping, wash the windows!
Эй, юнги! После пола вымойте окна!
Yes, sir!
Есть!
– One! Two! Three! Four!
Раз! Два! Три! Четыре!
I can't stand this. Forget Koby— why do I have to be a cabin boy?!
Не могу понять. Ладно ещё Коби, но почему я должен быть юнгой?!
Dammit! I only ended up here because of that Straw Hat!
Чёрт! Я очутился здесь только из-за Соломенной Шляпы!
It's all his fault!
Это его вина!
It's all because of Straw Hat that I'm stuck doing this crap!
Из-за Соломенной Шляпы мне приходится заниматься этим дерьмом!
Helmeppo.
Хельмеппо-сан.
What do you want?! Don't act like we're friends!
Чего тебе?! Мы с тобой не друзья!
Nothing good comes from blaming Luffy for everything that happens.
Если во всём обвинять Луффи-сана, это ни к чему вас не приведёт.
For a long time, you lived protected by your father's influence.
Долгое время вас, Хельмеппо-сан, защищала влиятельность вашего отца.
But from now on, we need to face forward and seek our own dreams!
Но теперь мы можем смотреть вперёд и искать собственные мечты!
What are you...?
Чего?!..
I have a dream.
У меня есть мечта.
Someday, I will be a Marine officer who cracks down on bad guys!
Однажды я стану дозорным, который сокрушает плохих парней!
What are you going on about?!
Да о чём ты вообще?!
A wimp like you becoming an officer for the Marines?!
Слабак типа тебя станет дозорным?!
Quit dreaming!
Проснись уже!
I will do it!
Точно стану!
I decided on it after seeing how Luffy lives his life!
Я решил, как только увидел Луффи-сана!
This is what I've decided, so if I die, then fine by me!
...и даже если умру, сражаясь, ну и ладно!
So just like Luffy, I've made up my mind to risk everything
Поэтому так же, как и Луффи-сан,
and pursue a goal of my own!
я решил идти к мечте!
You see? So let's work hard together!
Да? Так давайте работать вместе!
Screw you!
Иди к чёрту!
How dare you lecture me?!
Как ты смеешь учить меня?!
Just when did you get so full of yourself?!
Давно ты стал так уверен в себе?!
What could you possibly learn from that despicable Straw Hat?!
Чему ты вообще мог научиться у Соломенной Шляпы?!
Don't insult Luffy!
Не оскорбляйте Луффи-сана!
I haven't said anything wrong!
Я не сказал ничего глупого!
Wrong or not, you still piss me off!
Глупое или нет, но ты меня бесишь!
Helmeppo! Please! You have to be realistic.
Хельмеппо-сан, пожалуйста! Будьте реалистом!
Look who's talking!
Да кто бы говорил!
Take this!
Получай!
Get ahold of yourself!
Да очнитесь же!
Huh? What's going on?!
А? Что там такое?
– W-We're sorry! – We're sorry!
Про...
So then they kicked you out of the Marines?
И тогда вас выгнали из Дозора?
Thank you.
Приятного...
No, we managed to avoid being discharged.
Нет, нам удалось избежать увольнения.
But now we're under a fifty-year contract with no pay.
Но теперь мы на бесплатном контракте на пятьдесят лет.
Getting canned would've been a mercy.
А Коби это кажется честным.
Attention!
Внимание!
I will now fill you in on our current mission!
Я расскажу вам о нашей миссии!
– Hey! – What do you want?!
Эй, ты!
D-Daddy...
Па... папуль?..
Morgan, a former Marine captain, is to be sent to headquarters
Моргана, бывшего капитана Дозора, отправляют в штаб
to face a court-martial for the crimes of military exploitation and civilian torment!
предстать перед военным трибуналом за преступления по военной эксплуатации!
Today's mission is his transfer and delivery to Vice Admiral Garp!
Мы должны доставить его адмиралу Гарпу!
I am Captain "Axe-Hand" Morgan of the Marines!
Я — каперанг Морского Дозора "Топорорукий" Морган!
Scum without rank or status should kneel before me!
Любой без звания и статуса должен знать своё место!
This was the only outcome, wasn't it?
Это логичный итог, да?
I'm not denying that he should be court-martialed or whatever.
Я не отрицаю, что он должен предстать перед трибуналом.
He deserves what's coming to him, after all.
Всё-таки он это заслужил.
But even so, I used to respect him.
Но я всё равно уважал его.
Damn it!
Чёрт!
Why?!
Почему?!
Tell me, do you think they'll execute him?
Эй, как думаешь, отца казнят?
Th-That's...
Н-ну...
There's probably no getting around that either, huh?
Наверное, это тоже логично, да?
That's just how Daddy is.
Такой уж отец.
Helmeppo...
Хельмеппо-сан...
All hands on deck!
Свистать всех наверх!
Fall in!
Стройся!
– It's Vice Admiral Garp! – It's Garp the Fist!
Адмирал Гарп!
So that's Marine Headquarters' Vice Admiral Garp the Fist!
Так это — адмирал Морского Дозора "Кулак" Гарп?!
Traveling all over the Grand Line, he's the hero of the seas!
Герой морей, избороздивший Великий Путь!
Vice Admiral Garp, thank you for personally coming all this way!
Адмирал Гарп, приветствуем вас на борту!
We hereby deliver to you Morgan!
Морган подготовлен!
Stop, Helmeppo!
Успокойтесь, Хельмеппо-сан!
Umm... Vice Admiral Garp?
Эм... адмирал Гарп?
Vice Admiral Garp!
Адмирал Гарп!
Quiet!
Молчать!
I hear you.
Я слушаю.
I've been up for five days now.
Я не спал уже пять дней.
Thank you for your hard work, sir!
Спасибо за вашу работу!
It's no big deal since I'm trying for a new doughnut-eating record.
Нет, я пытаюсь побить мировой рекорд по поеданию пончиков.
But a lack of rest and sleep is getting to me after the 842nd one.
Но после восемьсот сорок второго пончика уже сказывается недостаток сна.
Old man, cut the sleeping act.
Старик, а ну, проснись.
Everybody freeze!
Всем ни с места!
Move and I'll hack up this cabin boy and feed him to the sharks!
Двинетесь, и я зарежу этого юнгу и скормлю акулам!
D-Daddy!
Па... папуль!
Please stop!
Пожалуйста, не надо!
Helmeppo's your own son, isn't he?!
Хельмеппо-сан ведь ваш собственный сын!
Son?! I don't need such a thing!
Сын!? Зачем он мне?!
What I want is freedom!
Мне нужна только свобода!
I'll smash him to a bloody pulp if need be!
Я размозжу ему череп, если понадобится!
D-Daddy...
Па... папуль?..
H-Help me!
По... помогите мне!
So long, suckers!
Пока, сосунки!
Helmeppo!
Хельмеппо-сан!
Ready the cannon!
Готовьте пушку!
Load! Aim!
Заряжай! Цельсь!
Target: 16 degrees starboard.
Цель — на шестнадцать градусов.
Distance: eight, two, six, three. Ready!
Дистанция — восемь, два, шесть, три. Готовьсь!
P-P-Please wait!
П... п-по... подождите!
That's dangerous!
Это опасно!
– What are you doing?! – Get down from there!
Чего удумал?! Слезай оттуда!
P-Please don't shoot! My friend...
Н-не стреляйте! Мой друг...
My friend's onboard!
Мой друг на борту!
Move.
Прочь.
No!
Нет уж!
Then I'll cut you down!
Я порежу тебя!
That's much better than just abandoning my friend!
Лучше так, чем предать своего друга!
Please! I'll go capture him myself!
Пожалуйста! Я сам его вызволю!
Come back, you idiot!
Идиот, вернись!
There's no way you can capture him!
Тебе никак его не вызволить!
Just let him go.
Пусть плывёт.
He's either a complete lunatic, or...
Либо он ненормальный, либо...
What do we do?!
Что делать?!
What's with all the racket? I'm finally awake.
Что тут происходит?! Я вроде выспался.
Vice Admiral Garp, we thought you were a goner!
Адмирал Гарп! Мы думали, вам конец!
I missed it because I was asleep! Where's the victim?!
Я пропустил удар, потому что спал. Кто жертва?
Me?
Ах, я?
I'm free!
Вот и свобода!
Just you watch! The world will kneel before me once again!
Увидите, мир ещё склонится передо мной!
Today, I begin a new life as the ruler of the Morgan Kingdom!
Сегодня я начну новую жизнь и создам своё королевство!
Now! Set our course west!
Итак! Курс на запад!
What are you doing?! I said to set course due west!
Чего сидишь?! Говорю же, курс на запад!
No!
Нет уж!
I'll have no part in this!
Я не буду помогать!
Despite what happened, he still covered for us!
После всего он всё равно прикрыл нас!
Even when getting sacked by the Marines would end his dream!
Даже если увольнение из Дозора уничтожит его мечту!
After all that, he's still protecting me! I can do it, too!
После всего он защищал меня! И я тоже буду!
I'm going to capture you, Dad! Just give up–
Отец, я захвачу тебя! Сдавай—
Are you dim?! Who do you think you're talking to, huh?!
Совсем дурак?! Ты хоть понимаешь, что несёшь?!
What can useless scum like you do to me?!
Что может против меня бесполезный кусок дерьма?!
Dammit!
Чёрт!
Know your place, you pathetic insect!
Знай своё место, жалкое насекомое!
As if I'd ever listen to you!
Я не буду тебя слушать!
I'm the one who decides how I'll live!
Я сам решу, как мне жить!
Quit getting the wrong idea! What can a piece of scum like you do?!
Перестань уже мечтать! Что может такой как ты?!
He isn't alone!
Он не одинок!
You!
Ты!..
Morgan!
Морган!
Pathetic! Pathetic! Pathetic!
Жалкий, жалкий, жалкий!
So what if a couple of insects are swarming together?!
И что же смогут двое насекомых?!
Get in my way, and I'll end you both in one fell swoop!
Встанете у меня на пути, и вам конец!
I'm sorry you got dragged into this when you tried to save me.
Прости, ты хотел спасти меня, и вот, что вышло.
What are you talking about?
О чём это вы?!
Aren't we friends?
Разве мы не друзья?!
Koby...
Коби...
You damn insects aren't even worth killing.
Насекомые не заслуживают смерти.
Never show yourselves to me again!
Не попадайтесь мне никогда!
Morgan!
Морган!
I'll let you go for today,
Сегодня я тебя отпускаю,
but someday I will surpass you!
но однажды ты не уйдёшь!
Someday, I will catch you!
Однажды я поймаю тебя!
Just you wait!
Жди!
Please forgive my poor supervision!
Простите, я не доглядел!
Letting him flee is the biggest blunder in my life!
Я виноват в том, что он сбежал!
We're very sorry, sir!
Нам очень жаль!
These two are now forever barred from military service!
Эти двое будут уволены со службы!
You two truly are lost causes.
Вы двое натворили дел.
I doubt anyone anywhere would take you in now.
Сомневаюсь, что кто-то возьмёт вас на службу.
And if we turn you loose, you'd be a nuisance to all.
А если отпустить, вы станете помехой.
You leave me no choice. Come with me to Marine Headquarters!
Делать нечего. Отправляйтесь со мной в штаб!
Vice Admiral! You're taking them with you to Marine Headquarters?!
Адмирал, вы забираете их с собой в Штаб Дозора?!
Am I not allowed?
А нельзя?
Any objections, you two?
Возражения, вы двое?
If you want to run away, now's your chance.
Это ваш шанс сбежать.
Though I have no intention of letting you say no.
Хотя я не приемлю отказа.
My, oh my, what an odd day this has been!
Надо же, какой странный день!
But doesn't he have an exceptional reputation?
Разве у него не особая репутация?
Yeah, you have no idea.
Да уж, ещё какая.
Then those two must show a lot of promise.
Значит, те двое ему чем-то приглянулись.
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
Дурак! Дурак! Дурак! Дурак!
Why did you let them go without saying anything?!
Почему ты отпустил их, не попрощавшись?!
Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid! Stupid!
Дурак! Дурак! Дурак! Дурак! Дурак!
I... wanted to play with them more.
Я... хотела ещё с ними поиграть...
I wanted to talk to them more.
Хотела поболтать с ними...
I was learning how to cook so I could make them tasty lunch boxes!
Я училась готовить и хотела угостить их своим бенто!
I didn't even get to say goodbye!
Мы с ними даже не попрощались!
Why did they leave?!
Почему они ушли?!
Ah, I'm sorry! Forgive me!
А, прости! Прости меня!
Rika, that's enough. Leave him alone.
Рика, хватит, оставь его.
Don't worry. They'll surely be back... once they become fine officers.
Не волнуйся. Они точно вернутся, когда станут офицерами.
But at any rate,
Но разве
can we really become Marines by doing things like this?
Штаб Морского Дозора
This might be that old dog's hobby, you know.
Может, это хобби старого пса?!
Hobby?
Хобби?
Yup. It's called "the retired geezer's torment of youths."
Ага. Типа, "издевательство пенсионера над молодёжью".
Don't you think he's shifty and strange enough for that?
Разве это невозможно, учитывая его хитрость?
Shut up, birds!
Заткнитесь, птицы!